CASANDRA CUTTER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A full stack developer with fifteen years experience in education and a background in the arts, ready to deploy strong communication skills and a creative thought process to the development cycle. Self-directed and enthusiastic learner with superior design and analytical skills prepared to join a collaborative, innovative team environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- o HTML
- o CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- o jQuery
- o GIT

- Github
- Media Queries
- APIs
- o JSON
- o AJAX
- Command line

- o Node.Js
- o React.js
- React Native
- MySQL
- MongoDB

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Application development
- o Strategic Planning
- Partnership development
- Client Service

- Project Management
- Verbal and written communication
- Relationship building

APPLICATIONS BUILT

NIGHT IN

A mobile-first application that uses multiple APIs to retrieve movie selections, recipes, and cocktails based on user input.

Lead HTML and CSS developer and project manager of a group of four

Deployed Application - Night In

DAY PLANNER

A simple calendar application that allows the user to save events for each hour of the workday.

Independently developed using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

Deployed Application - Day Planner

WEATHER DASHBOARD

A weather dashboard application that uses API to retrieve weather data for cities input by the user.

Independently developed using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, OpenWeather API

Deployed Application - Weather Dashboard

WORK HISTORY

BLUEMILK SALON + CREATIVE SPACE — Owner and Stylist

SAN ANTONIO, TX - AUGUST 2016 - PRESENT

PAUL MITCHELL ADVANCED EDUCATION - Advanced Academy Educator

SAN ANTONIO, TX - FEBRUARY 2013 - DECEMBER 2016

PAUL MITCHELL THE SCHOOL - Cosmetology Instructor

SAN ANTONIO, TX - APRIL 2008 - OCTOBER 2016

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS SAN ANTONIO - Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

SAN ANTONIO, TX - EXPECTED COMPLETION JANUARY 2021

PAUL MITCHELL THE SCHOOL - Cosmetology Instructor's License DALLAS, TX - 2008

PAUL MITCHELL THE SCHOOL - Cosmetology License DALLAS, TX - 2007

HERRON SCHOOL OF ART AND DESIGN - Fine Art INDIANAPOLIS, IN - 2005